

# **Profile**

Passionate and motivated software developer based in Milan with 2 years of professional experience developing with C# and Unity

Interested in all kinds of technologies, in particular everything regarding Shaders, Videogames, AR/VR/XR, and AI.

I think the best part of our job is to find a new problem to solve and nothing gratifies me the most than doing it.

I've spent 5 years working in the family business to pay for my studies, which's lead me to understand even more how much I love coding and in particular solving problems.

# **Employment History**

Software Developer (C# - Unity), UpSurgeOn Srl, Milano

MARCH 2020 - PRESENT

UpSurgeOn develops a technologically advanced sequence of virtual and physical technologies designed to support Mental and Manual training and advance cognitive and motor skills to solve the problem of Training in neurosurgery which is a global healthcare emergency.

UpSurgeOn won the European Union's H2020 Research and Innovation Programme.

During my period working there as a Software developer on Unity I was able to focus on:

C#, Unity, Online Stores Management, ARCore - ARKit, Shaders, UI, In-Depth Code optimization, Services (Savings, In-App Purchase, News), Database, Online Server API, Camera Behaviours

Professor of "Shader Basics", The Sign Comics & Arts Academy, Florence

OCTOBER 2019 - MARCH 2020

The Sign Comics & Arts Academy is a private university that offers courses on all kinds of disciplines related to game development

After my graduation, the academy offered me a 6 months job as a professor to teach new programmers my thesis subject.

It was an incredible experience teaching young game programmers about a subject that I love that much

# Education

Game Programmer, Event Horizon School / TheSign Comics & Arts Academy, Florence

SEPTEMBER 2016 - SEPTEMBER 2019

Final thesis: Shader (CG-HLSL)

3 Year course with focus on:

C#, C++, Unity, Teamwork, Working with artists and designers, working with other developers, multiplatform

#### **Details**

Milan

Italy

+39 3935667302

giacomo vanni@yahoo.it

NATIONALITY

Italian

DATE / PLACE OF BIRTH

22/11/1993

Pis:

### Links

Portfolio with complete projects track

### **Skills**

C#

Unity

Git

Shader (CG - HLSL)

C++

OOP

**HTML-CSS** 

Working with Designers/Artists

### Languages

Italian

English

#### **Hobbies**

Videogames, Card games, Tennis, Skiing

#### Computer Engineering, University of Pisa

SEPTEMBER 2014 - NOVEMBER 2014

Although I didn't complete that course, I spent 2 years attending classes and exams.

I learned the principles of Programming, OOP, and attended courses of Algorithm and Data Structures, Operating System, Math and Physic

# Courses

Shader Development using Unity, https://shaderdev.com/p/shader-development-using-unity-5

JANUARY 2018 - JANUARY 2019

# Extra-curricular activities

#### Receptionist, Dimora Antico Borgo, Terricciola

JANUARY 2012 - JANUARY 2019

To pay for my studies I've joined the family business and start handling social media and welcoming customers for our B&B/ Apartment service in Tuscany. where I learn in-depth knowledge on how to work and relate with customers

# Internships

### Unity Developer (Microsoft HoloLens), Balzo Srl, Florence

MAY 2016 - SEPTEMBER 2016

After I've finished my first year at the academy, one of my professors offered me an internship at his company.

For four months I've worked hand to hand with senior developers using Microsoft HoloLens

### References

References available upon request